<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: philosophy | Vinícius Teles]]></title>
  <link href="http://viniciusteles.com/blog/categories/philosophy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://viniciusteles.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-23T07:44:11-02:00</updated>
  <id>http://viniciusteles.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinícius Teles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autonomy is so underrated]]></title>
    <link href="http://viniciusteles.com/autonomy-is-so-underrated"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://viniciusteles.com/autonomy-is-so-underrated</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Choose your goals wisely because you may actually get what you want! You better aim at something meaningful. <p /> Most people seem to want at least one thing in common: more money. The thinking is that if you have more money, than you can have more stuff and do more stuff. And this somehow translates into being happier. <p /> Unfortunately, that doesn't seem to be the case. Money is a very important tool and as such, having it can be quite helpful. So it makes sense to try to have at least enough money to do what you want. Having more won't hurt, though. On the other hand, there's only so much you can do if you can't control your own time. <br />As it turns out, time and autonomy to use your time as you wish is far more meaningful and life changing than only having money. Having more and more money but no time and autonomy to use it is not particularly meaningful and it's a waste in itself. <p /> Pati and I travel around the world permanently not because we have a lot of money. Actually, we probably earn less than most people we know with equivalent qualifications. We do travel because we have autonomy over our time and we use whatever money we have carefully. <p /> It took us a while and some serious focus to achieve this level of autonomy. But most of all, it required an understanding of what we should focus on: autonomy and freedom. Unfortunately, they're so underrated.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: to my friends in the technology field I must add that software developers are probably some of the most priviledged people when it comes to achieving a great deal of autonomy, as long as they aim at it, of course. Fortunately, one can write software wherever and whenever they want to. A humble taxi driver reminded me of that a few days ago, here in Kuala Lumpur. ;-)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
